Kyle Davis

Norman, OK | (405) 413-0606 | kyledaviswx@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/kyleldavis

Full Stack Developer | Drupal Developer | Author

Professional Summary

Full stack web developer with 15+ years of experience. Proficient in all areas of web development and design. Experience in managing, developing, and maintaining multiple large-scale web and Drupal projects. Prioritizes developing websites and applications that are reliable, easy to use, efficient, and most importantly, accessible to all. Works extremely well with peers and strives to avoid complacency by frequently learning new languages and platforms.

Key Skills, Languages, and Platforms

- Project Management
- Agile Workflow
- Customer Support
- Unit testing
- Javascript
- ES6
- Node.js
- React
- PHP
- MySQL MSSQL
- NoSQL
- HTML Twig

• CSS

AWS

• Drupal 7/8/9/10

Adobe CC

- Composer Docker
- Graphic design/UI • Git
 - CI/CD

 - npm

Professional Experience

Senior Drupal Developer/Team Lead | University of Oklahoma Libraries | 2018 - Present

- · Manager of web team as well as the web steering committee.
- Migration of large, high-traffic website from Drupal 7 to Drupal 10 (libraries.ou.edu). Migration included new theme and design, platform change to Pantheon, and large amount of technical improvements and accessibility.
- Manage and maintain many other legacy sites in Drupal 7. Currently archiving, migrating, and consolidating them.
- · Created workflow and documentation for local ddev environments of migrated Drupal 10 sites.
- Responsible for the website's WCAG AA 2.1 accessibility compliance and implemented the Monsido accessibility tool.

Full Stack Bootcamp Instructor | University of Minnesota with edX/2U | 2022 - 2023

- Instructor for remote full-stack coding bootcamp.
- Instructed a wide variety of languages and skills including: html, css, JS, REST API's, SQL, Node.is, Express.is, mongodb, PWA's, React, and the MERN stack.
- Mentored students with my professional experience and helped build their portfolios and skills to start their career.

Web Developer | Oklahoma Climatological Survey/Mesonet | 2015-2018

- Created and deployed the Mesonet's first Drupal site for the U.S.D.A Agricultural Research Service ARS (ars.mesonet.org).
- Implemented a complete re-work of the Mesonet OK-FIRE website. The product was very outdated and contained complex meteorological equations and formulas. Simplified hundreds of pages down to a manageable and effective tool. Site can be seen at mesonet.org/index.php/okfire.
- · Created SVG weather widgets that retrieve live weather data and displays dynamically in the lobby of the National Weather Center in Norman, OK.

Other Career Experience

- Self-published author and creator of children's coding book Bit and Byte: Hunt for the sunken treasure.
- AWS Systems Operations certification.
- Full application and web developer for billiard product. Utilized Twilio api, AWS, S3, EC2, RDS, Elastic beanstalk.
- Engineering and programming an Arduino board to physically interface with the pool table and the application.
- One of the main developers at an online casino gaming start up, Redibids. Launched a large scale live auction site.
- Map and product developer at Weather Decision Technologies (now DTN).
- iOS application developer sole creator of an app for pet training.

Education

University of Oklahoma - 2009

- · Bachelor's of Science in Meteorology
- · Minor in Mathematics
- Minor in Broadcast Meteorology and Mass Communication